export const questionsAndAnswers = [
  {
    question:
      "In more recent times, the Master Scientist philosophical doctrine has come to be known as ___.",
    answer: "Scientism",
  },
  {
    question:
      "According to ________, philosophy is rightly called the knowledge of the truth.",
    answer: "Aristotle",
  },
  {
    question:
      "An important characteristic of philosophy is that it consists in the constant and unwavering disposition to seek the truth. True or False ____",
    answer: "True",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Examination and confirmation of the universal acceptance of moral views held by human beings or the society is the responsibility of ______",
    answer: "Descriptive ethics",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Observation and understanding supernatural phenomenon and control processes is the main task of _______",
    answer: "Science",
  },
  {
    question: "Philosophy has no univocal definition. True or False _____",
    answer: "True",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The method of _____ takes reason to be the sole means of acquiring philosophical knowledge.",
    answer: "Rationalism",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The philosophical idea that establishes the world as a product of a single understanding substance is known as ______",
    answer: "Monism",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The method of rationalism takes reason to be the sole means of acquiring philosophical knowledge. True or False ________",
    answer: "True",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The critical or transcendental method of philosophy ______takes stock of the arguments of empiricism and rationalism and builds a new system of tremendous importance in the history of philosophic thought.",
    answer: "Kant",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ method of philosophy consists in the constructive dialectical process of opposition and reconciliation.",
    answer: "Hegel",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Identifying a complex argument involves a complex reasoning. True or False ____",
    answer: "True",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_______ arguments are those in which the premises do not lead to the conclusion with certainty.",
    answer: "Inductive",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The branch of philosophy that studies reality in its most comprehensive scope is ____",
    answer: "Metaphysics",
  },
  {
    question: "_____ is also referred to as the science of human conduct.",
    answer: "Ethics",
  },
  {
    question:
      "To claim the knowledge of anything, one must possess correct_____ about the thing.",
    answer: "Information",
  },
  {
    question: "The idea that only change is constant is from ______.",
    answer: "Heraclitus",
  },
  {
    question:
      "We have knowledge only when we can NOT provide reasons and evidence for our claims. True or False ____",
    answer: "False",
  },
  {
    question:
      "According to _______, water is the primary source of all things in the universe.",
    answer: "Thales",
  },
  {
    question:
      "According to ____ happiness could best be achieved by living a balanced life and avoiding excess by pursuing a golden mean in everything.",
    answer: "Aristotle",
  },
  {
    question:
      "To the ______ we can never know the true inner substance of things, only how they appear to us.",
    answer: "Sceptics",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Nationalist and ideological philosophy is also known as a sub of______ in African philosophy.",
    answer: "Professional philosophy",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_______was largely a religious philosophy which became a strong influence on early Christianity (especially on St. Augustine).",
    answer: "Neo-Platonism",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Condensation and Refraction theory was developed to justify ___ as the primary source of all things.",
    answer: "Air",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The weakness or strength of an Inductive argument depends on the degree of evidence contained in the conclusion. True or False ______",
    answer: "True",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Denotative definition is one that attempts to identify the extension of the term in a question. True or False ______",
    answer: "True",
  },
  {
    question:
      "According to the Law of Identity, not everything you say presupposes that thing. True or False ____",
    answer: "False",
  },
  {
    question: "In a disjunctive syllogism, the first premise is a _______.",
    answer: "Disjunction",
  },
  {
    question:
      "It is through the possession of language by human beings that their thought and conduct are made possible. True or False _______",
    answer: "True",
  },
  { question: "Argumentum ad Baculum means ______", answer: "Appeal to force" },
  {
    question:
      "_____ fallacy mostly occurs when we misinterpret someone’s original statement or intention.",
    answer: "Amphiboly",
  },
  {
    question: "Fallacy of Begging the question is also known as ____",
    answer: "Petito-principii",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______definition does not attempt overcoming ambiguity or to achieve precision rather it focuses on formulating a theory within which a fully correct definition of important terms could be stated.",
    answer: "Theoretical",
  },
  {
    question:
      "According to the law of_______, you cannot refuse to be this and also refuse to be the other.",
    answer: "Excluded middle",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The law of _______ tells you that a thing must be one thing or another thing.",
    answer: "Non-contradiction",
  },
  { question: "Philosophy grew out of", answer: "Wonder and Curiosity" },
  {
    question:
      "One of the following is a fundamental factor that determines the definition of philosophy",
    answer: "Issues",
  },
  {
    question:
      "To wonder about life and every issue that borders on human existence is",
    answer: "Philosophical activity",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The conception of philosophy as a person’s attitude or principle is called",
    answer: "Under labourer",
  },
  {
    question: "The empiricist conception of truth or reality is based on",
    answer: "Sense experience",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is referred to as the science of reasoning?",
    answer: "Logic",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The idea of epistemology was explained using the idea of world of 'Forms' by",
    answer: "Plato",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following philosophers is NOT a member of the Medieval age of philosophy?",
    answer: "Berkeley",
  },
  {
    question: "The medieval philosophers employed philosophy to teach",
    answer: "Religion",
  },
  {
    question:
      "An attempt to become aware and to doubt all preconceptions and the essence in order to ensure certainty in the process is called",
    answer: "Scepticism",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following grew after the traditional branches of philosophy?",
    answer: "Feminism",
  },
  { question: "The author of synthetic a priori knowledge is", answer: "Kant" },
  {
    question: "Philosophical knowledge is believed to follow the logic of",
    answer: "Proposition",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is an Islamic philosopher in the Medieval period?",
    answer: "Averroes",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What kind of argument is 'Most mechanics are dark in complexion, Yisa is a mechanic, therefore Yisa is dark in complexion'?",
    answer: "Inductive",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following branches of philosophy has been defined as the science of being as being?",
    answer: "Metaphysics",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The first philosopher to confess that 'the only thing I know is that I know nothing' is",
    answer: "Socrates",
  },
  {
    question: "Which group holds a relativistic view of knowledge?",
    answer: "Sophism",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Era of the Ionians was dominated by the following philosophers EXCEPT",
    answer: "Zeno of Citium",
  },
  {
    question: "Natural philosophy gave rise to the following EXCEPT",
    answer: "Culture",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Greek philosophers were said to have had contact with and influenced by",
    answer: "Egyptian philosophy",
  },
  {
    question:
      "That pleasure is the most important pursuit of mankind, and that we should always act so as to maximize our own pleasure is the philosophical position of the",
    answer: "Hedonists",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What are the opposing doctrines that characterized The Age of Reason and The Age of Enlightenment?",
    answer: "Rationalism and Empiricism",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What form of function is performed by language when the utterance operates to evoke action from the hearer?",
    answer: "Directive",
  },
  {
    question:
      "'I shall contest the next election,' is an example of what function of language?",
    answer: "Performative",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is NOT an informal fallacy?",
    answer: "Four term",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What fallacy is committed in the argument: 'Only man is rational. But no woman is a man. Therefore, no woman is rational.'?",
    answer: "Equivocation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What kind of definitions is directed at developing a coherent theoretical account of the subject at hand?",
    answer: "Theoretical",
  },
  {
    question: "'All students' falls under what category of proposition?",
    answer: "Universal affirmative",
  },
  {
    question: "Recursive definition is sometimes referred to as",
    answer: "Inductive",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The words Definiendum and definiens are key concepts in the method of definition by",
    answer: "Genus and Difference",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q1 __ is regarded as a group of propositions whose function is to make a claim about something",
    options: ["dissertation", "law", "argument", "philosophy"],
    answer: "argument",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q2 Logos, the Greek word from which Logic derived does not mean ___",
    options: ["discourse", "word", "study", "life"],
    answer: "study",
  },
  {
    question: "Q3 The Greek word for wisdom is ___",
    options: ["sophia", "philosophy", "philo", "alethia"],
    answer: "sophia",
  },
  {
    question: "Q4 Philosophy is the only discipline that is ___ in nature",
    options: ["old", "universal", "scientific", "atheistic"],
    answer: "universal",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q5 Aristotle holds that understanding philosophy entails mastering ___",
    options: ["other sciences", "theology", "God", "atheism"],
    answer: "other sciences",
  },
  {
    question: "Q6 The natural sciences broke away from philosophy in ___",
    options: ["18th century", "19th century", "17th century", "20th century"],
    answer: "17th century",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q7 ___ writings were regarded as Encyclopedia of philosophy by the medieval men",
    options: ["Plato", "Pythagoras", "Aristotle", "Augustine"],
    answer: "Aristotle",
  },
  {
    question: "Q8 Anaximenes was the first to explain ___",
    options: [
      "cause of rainbow",
      "eclipse of the sun",
      "the regenerative power of music",
      "that man evolved from fishes",
    ],
    answer: "cause of rainbow",
  },
  {
    question: "Q9 Thales predicted ___ in 585 B.C",
    options: [
      "death of King Herod",
      "Coming of Jesus",
      "Global famine",
      "Eclipse",
    ],
    answer: "Eclipse",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q10 Which of these was not among the pre-colonial regional capitals",
    options: ["Enugu", "Kaduna", "Lagos", "Ibadan"],
    answer: "Enugu",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q11 In dividing Nigeria into Eastern and Western regions __ was used as the boundary",
    options: ["Ndiukwuenu Forest", "Ikom River", "River Niger", "River Benue"],
    answer: "River Niger",
  },
  {
    question: "Q12 ___ regarded fire as the primary substance of all reality",
    options: ["Locke", "Anaximander", "Anaximenes", "Heraclitus"],
    answer: "Heraclitus",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q13 Thales identified ___ as the primary substance of the universe",
    options: ["ashes", "cold", "water", "sand"],
    answer: "water",
  },
  {
    question: "Q14 ___ is not among the sources of philosophy",
    options: [
      "curiosity",
      "sense of wonder",
      "desire for knowledge for its sake",
      "idleness and poverty",
    ],
    answer: "idleness and poverty",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q15 The first standard comment about the nature and definition of philosophy was made by ___",
    options: ["Pythagoras", "Isaac Newton", "Plato", "Aristotle"],
    answer: "Plato",
  },
  {
    question: "Q16 ___ had his philosophical training in Africa",
    options: ["Plato", "Pythagoras", "Augustine", "Confucius"],
    answer: "Augustine",
  },
  {
    question: "Q17 Western Philosophy originated in___",
    options: ["Miletus", "Rome", "Athens", "Sicily"],
    answer: "Athens",
  },
  {
    question: "Q18 'Honesty is my best policy' is an expression of ____",
    options: [
      "One's religious belief",
      "One's philosophy of life",
      "Declaration of one's honesty",
      "Manifestation of one's righteousness",
    ],
    answer: "One's philosophy of life",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q19 The hotel manager with a degree in food and nutrition is heard referring to herself as a philosopher. Her doing so is regarded as ___",
    options: [
      "impersonation",
      "double assumption of identity",
      "false identification",
      "layman use of the term",
    ],
    answer: "layman use of the term",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q20 Every philosopher defines philosophy in his or her own way because philosophy is ___",
    options: ["old discipline", "complex", "hard", "everyday wisdom"],
    answer: "complex",
  },
  {
    question: "Q21 Deny the following statement: 'I am a thief' __",
    options: [
      "It is you that is a thief",
      "No, I am not a thief",
      "There is no single thief in my family",
      "It is my father that was once a thief",
    ],
    answer: "No, I am not a thief",
  },
  {
    question: "Q22 ___ and ___ qualify a statement as logical",
    options: [
      "truth and observability",
      "deniability and assertability",
      "conditionality and proportionality",
      "contradiction and inferability",
    ],
    answer: "truth and observability",
  },
  {
    question: "Q23 In logic, another name for statement is ___",
    options: ["truth", "proposition", "fact of matter", "conceptual analysis"],
    answer: "proposition",
  },
  {
    question: "Q24 __ is not among the three divisions of formal logic",
    options: [
      "logic of propositions",
      "logic of terms",
      "logic of assumptions",
      "logic of relations",
    ],
    answer: "logic of assumptions",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q25 ___ is the logical process exhibited in this statement: All lecturers are homosexuals",
    options: ["simple apprehension", "judgement", "intuition", "reasoning"],
    answer: "reasoning",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q26 In logic, when the mind forms the concept of anything we say that ___ has taken place",
    options: ["judgement", "intuition", "reasoning", "simple apprehension"],
    answer: "simple apprehension",
  },
  {
    question: "Q27 Man's ability to think is regarded as ___",
    options: ["ethics", "reason", "sensibility", "productivity"],
    answer: "reason",
  },
  {
    question: "Q28 ___ is not a source of knowledge",
    options: ["gossip", "intuition", "reason", "faith"],
    answer: "gossip",
  },
  {
    question: "Q29 ___ is not a branch of ethics",
    options: [
      "meta ethics",
      "normative ethics",
      "descriptive ethics",
      "causative ethics",
    ],
    answer: "causative ethics",
  },
  {
    question: "Q30 Another name for ethics is called ____",
    options: ["moral philosophy", "materialism", "characater", "empiricism"],
    answer: "moral philosophy",
  },
  {
    question: "Q31 _____ is the concern of ethics",
    options: ["what is", "what was", "what ought to be", "what will be"],
    answer: "what ought to be",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q32 The saying that unexamined life is not worth living is attributable to ___",
    options: ["Manford", "Aristotle", "Socrates", "Kukah"],
    answer: "Socrates",
  },
  {
    question: "Q33 ___ branch of philosophy is regarded as theory of knowledge",
    options: ["physicalism", "epistemology", "metaphysics", "logic"],
    answer: "epistemology",
  },
  {
    question: "Q34 Aristotle named his book that deals with nature ___",
    options: ["versmeneutic", "Oncology", "Physics", "De Anima"],
    answer: "Physics",
  },
  {
    question: "Q35 ___ is regarded as the study of first principles",
    options: [
      "ethics",
      "metalogical deontic logics",
      "politics",
      "metaphysics",
    ],
    answer: "metaphysics",
  },
  {
    question: "Q36 An argument that rests on probability is called ___",
    options: [
      "deductive argument",
      "inductive argument",
      "rational argument",
      "empirical argument",
    ],
    answer: "inductive argument",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q37 Draw the conclusion of this argument: All lecturers will go to heaven; Dr Uthman is a lecturer; therefore__",
    options: [
      "Dr Uthman is an exception",
      "Dr Uthman will go to heaven",
      "I have seen a lecturer involved in evil",
      "False, bad lecturers will not go to heaven",
    ],
    answer: "Dr Uthman will go to heaven",
  },
  {
    question: "Q38 Deductive argument move from __ to ___",
    options: [
      "up to down",
      "general to particular",
      "particular to general",
      "from horizontal to perpendicular",
    ],
    answer: "general to particular",
  },
  {
    question: "Q39 Arguments are either deductive or ___",
    options: ["doxastic", "imperative", "inductive", "argumentative"],
    answer: "inductive",
  },
  {
    question: "Q40 In standard argument conclusion is inferred from __",
    options: ["debate", "premises", "formality", "symbolism"],
    answer: "premises",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q41 The fallacy that misrepresents a fact, and then goes ahead to attack that misrepresentation is called ___ fallacy",
    options: ["bandwagon", "ad hominem", "straw man", "accusatory"],
    answer: "straw man",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q42 'If you see any lecturer supporting the current administration, that person has been paid heavily.' This is an example of ___",
    options: ["fallacy", "ad hominem", "straw man", "bandwagon", "accusatory"],
    answer: "ad hominem",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q43 In informal fallacies___ does not render an argument fallacious",
    options: [
      "at least one premise is false",
      "emotions are appeal to",
      "argument lacks structure",
      "arguments are not about the thesis under consideration",
    ],
    answer: "arguments are not about the thesis under consideration",
  },
  {
    question: "Q44 Errors in reasoning are called ___",
    options: ["irrationality", "fallacies", "mindset", "aberration"],
    answer: "fallacies",
  },
  {
    question: "Q45 ___ is not among Haliday's function of language",
    options: ["heuristic", "imaginative", "regulatory", "commissive"],
    answer: "commissive",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q46 If you have ever heard of the book; 'How to do things with words', kindly identify ___ as the author",
    options: ["Socrates", "J. L. Austin", "Wole Soyinka", "Nelson Mandela"],
    answer: "J. L. Austin",
  },
  {
    question: "Q47 The abbreviation, L. A. D. means ____",
    options: [
      "Logic and Development",
      "Linguistic Advancement Conference",
      "Legal Advancement Digital",
      "Language Acquisition Device",
    ],
    answer: "Language Acquisition Device",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q48 'It shall be well with you,' the pastor thundered to the congregation. ___ function of language is at play here",
    options: [
      "emotive function",
      "blessing function",
      "declarative function",
      "deductive function",
    ],
    answer: "blessing function",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Q49 Jamiu raised the veil that covered the face of his new bride, 'I will be with you till the end of my life.' ___ is the function of language expressed here",
    options: [
      "expressive function",
      "informative function",
      "commissive function",
      "directive function",
    ],
    answer: "commissive function",
  },
];
